<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata><idinfo><citation><citeinfo><origin>Scott Prinos</origin><pubdate>20190401</pubdate><title>Approximate inland extent of saltwater interface in the Biscayne aquifer in 2018, Miami-Dade County, Fl,</title><geoform>Vector Digital Data Set (Polyline)</geoform><onlink>https://doi.org/10.5066/xxxxxxxxx</onlink><lworkcit><citeinfo><origin>Scott T. Prinos</origin><pubdate>2019</pubdate><title>Map of the Approximate Inland Extent of Saltwater at the Base of the Biscayne Aquifer in Miami-Dade County, Florida, 2018</title><edition>1</edition><geoform>Publication (Other)</geoform><serinfo><sername>Scientific Investigations Map</sername><issue>2019–XXXX</issue></serinfo><pubinfo><pubplace>Reston VA</pubplace><publish>U.S. Geological Survey</publish></pubinfo><othercit>Sonenshein, R.S., 1997, Delineation and Extent of Saltwater Intrusion in the Biscayne Aquifer, Eastern Dade County, Florida, 1995: U.S. Geological Survey Water Resources Investigation Report 96-4285.</othercit><onlink>https://doi.org/10.3133/XXXXX</onlink></citeinfo></lworkcit></citeinfo></citation><descript><abstract>The U.S. Geological Survey (USGS), in cooperation with Miami-Dade County, mapped the approximate inland extent of saltwater intrusion in eastern Miami-Dade County in 2018. This approximation required acquisition and compilation of relevant data collected by the organizations: Florida Department of Environmental Protection (FDEP), Florida Keys Aqueduct Authority (FKAA), Florida Power &amp; Light Company (FPL), MacVicar Consulting Inc., Miami-Dade County Regulatory and Economic Resources (MD-RER),  the South Florida Water Management District (SFWMD), and the USGS. Data from the selected monitoring wells were entered into a geographic information system (GIS) for analysis and mapping. The approximate saltwater interface is represented by the 1,000-mg/L isochlor at the base of the Biscayne aquifer. The word “approximate” is used because the spatial distribution of monitoring wells is generally insufficient to create a precise representation.</abstract><purpose>The inland extent of saltwater at the base of the Biscayne aquifer in Miami-Dade County was last mapped in 2011. In 2016 the extent of saltwater intrusion in the southeastern part of Miami-Dade County called the Model Land area was mapped. An updated map was required because saltwater intrusion continues to occur in the county. This is a concern because it can render the water unpotable in effected parts of the aquifer. The maximum concentration of chloride allowed in drinking water is 250 milligrams per liter  whereas saltwater-intruded parts of the aquifer commonly have water with chloride concentrations of 1,000 mg/L or greater.</purpose></descript><timeperd><timeinfo><sngdate><caldate>2018</caldate></sngdate></timeinfo><current>observed</current></timeperd><status><progress>Complete</progress><update>Irregular</update></status><spdom><bounding><westbc>-80.529861388</westbc><eastbc>-80.165397205</eastbc><northbc>25.979469129</northbc><southbc>25.322904204</southbc></bounding></spdom><keywords><theme><themekt>ISO 19115 Topic Category</themekt><themekey>geoscientificInformation</themekey></theme><theme><themekt>USGS Thesaurus</themekt><themekey>geochemistry</themekey><themekey>maps and atlases</themekey><themekey>hydrology</themekey><themekey>saltwater intrusion</themekey></theme><theme><themekt>USGS information products</themekt><themekey>Scientific Investigations Map</themekey></theme><theme><themekt>Alexandria Digital Library Feature Type Thesaurus</themekt><themekey>aquifers</themekey></theme><theme><themekt>None</themekt><themekey>Biscayne Aquifer</themekey></theme><place><placekt>none</placekt><placekey>United States</placekey><placekey>Florida</placekey><placekey>Dade county</placekey><placekey>Miami</placekey><placekey>Biscayne aquifer</placekey><placekey>Model Land area</placekey></place><place><placekt>Common geographic areas</placekt><placekey>Miami-Dade</placekey><placekey>Florida Bay-Florida Keys</placekey><placekey>Florida</placekey><placekey>Southern Florida</placekey><placekey>United States</placekey></place></keywords><accconst>None</accconst><useconst>None</useconst><ptcontac><cntinfo><cntorgp><cntorg>U.S. Geological Survey, Southeast Region</cntorg><cntper>Scott T Prinos</cntper></cntorgp><cntpos>Hydrologist</cntpos><cntaddr><addrtype>mailing address</addrtype><address>3321 College Avenue</address><city>Davie</city><state>FL</state><postal>33314</postal><country>United States</country></cntaddr><cntvoice>954-377-5944</cntvoice><cntfax>954-377-5901</cntfax><cntemail>stprinos@usgs.gov</cntemail></cntinfo></ptcontac><browse><browsen>D:\users\stprinos\gis\SalinityProject\SaltlineBiscayne2008.shp</browsen><browsed>Approximate inland extent of saltwater interface in the Biscayne aquifer in 2008, Miami-Dade County, Fl</browsed><browset>GIF</browset></browse><native>Environment as of Metadata Creation: Microsoft [Unknown] Version 6.2 (Build 9200) ; Esri ArcGIS 10.4.1 (Build 5686) Service Pack N/A (Build N/A)</native></idinfo><dataqual><attracc><attraccr>The accuracy and precision of this approximation is best evaluated on a location-by-location basis given the distribution of available monitoring wells. The locations of the monitoring wells and the chloride concentration values are shown on the map (see larger work citation). The line depicting the approximate inland extent of saltwater is dashed where the monitoring well distribution is insufficient to create a reasonably accurate and precise approximation.</attraccr></attracc><logic>The data set was checked for topological consistency.</logic><complete>This data set contains data for eastern Miami-Dade county, Fl It does not extend into the southern Everglades where the last avialble data was from  airborne and groundbased geophysical surveys collected in 1994-95,</complete><posacc><horizpa><horizpar>A formal accuracy assessment of the horizontal positional information in the data set has not been conducted.</horizpar></horizpa><vertacc><vertaccr>A formal accuracy assessment of the vertical positional information in the data set has either not been conducted, or is not applicable.</vertaccr></vertacc></posacc><lineage><procstep><procdesc>The GIS shapefile of Prinos and others (2014) was used as a starting place. 
This map was edited and modified to reflect the extent of saltwater intrusion in the Biscayne aquifer in 2018 based on salinity data collected from monitoring wells in 2018.
Reference
Prinos, S.T., Wacker, M.A., Cunningham, K.J., and Fitterman, D.V., 2014, Origins and delineation of saltwater intrusion in the Biscayne aquifer and changes in the distribution of saltwater in Miami-Dade County, Florida: U.S. Geological Survey Scientific Investigations Report 2014–5025, 101 p., http://dx.doi.org/10.3133/sir20145025</procdesc><procdate>20181230</procdate></procstep></lineage></dataqual><spdoinfo><direct>Vector</direct><ptvctinf><sdtsterm><sdtstype>String</sdtstype><ptvctcnt>9</ptvctcnt></sdtsterm></ptvctinf></spdoinfo><spref><horizsys><planar><gridsys><gridsysn>State Plane Coordinate System 1983</gridsysn><spcs><spcszone>0901</spcszone><transmer><feast>656166.666667</feast><fnorth>0.0</fnorth><longpc>-81.0</longpc><latprjc>24.3333333333</latprjc></transmer></spcs></gridsys><planci><plance>coordinate pair</plance><coordrep><absres>[Unknown]</absres><ordres>[Unknown]</ordres></coordrep><plandu>Foot_US</plandu></planci></planar><geodetic><horizdn>D_North_American_1983</horizdn><ellips>GRS_1980</ellips><semiaxis>6378137.0</semiaxis><denflat>298.257222101</denflat></geodetic></horizsys></spref><eainfo><detailed><enttyp><enttypl>Attribute Table</enttypl><enttypd>Table containing attribute information associated with the data set.</enttypd><enttypds>Producer defined</enttypds></enttyp><attr><attrlabl>OBJECTID</attrlabl><attrdef>Internal feature number.</attrdef><attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs><attrdomv><rdom><rdommin>1</rdommin><rdommax>8</rdommax></rdom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>SYMBOL</attrlabl><attrdef>A numeric symbol code designating the type of line that should be used for plotting</attrdef><attrdefs>USGS</attrdefs><attrdomv><rdom><rdommin>303</rdommin><rdommax>315</rdommax></rdom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>LINETYPE</attrlabl><attrdef>A description of the type of line that should be used for plotting. Dashed lines are approximately located, solid lines are inferred from data</attrdef><attrdefs>USGS</attrdefs><attrdomv><edom><edomv>dashed</edomv><edomvd>Use a dashed line when plotting line</edomvd><edomvds>Producer defined</edomvds></edom></attrdomv><attrdomv><edom><edomv>solid</edomv><edomvd>Use a dashed line when plotting line</edomvd><edomvds>Producer defined</edomvds></edom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>Length_m</attrlabl><attrdef>Mapped length of the line segment in meters.</attrdef><attrdefs>Producer defined</attrdefs><attrdomv><rdom><rdommin>2122.55743375</rdommin><rdommax>28670.5812614</rdommax><attrunit>meters</attrunit></rdom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>Length_ft</attrlabl><attrdef>Mapped length of the line segment in feet</attrdef><attrdefs>Producer defined</attrdefs><attrdomv><rdom><rdommin>6963.75718055</rdommin><rdommax>94063.3986885</rdommax><attrunit>feet</attrunit></rdom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>EndY</attrlabl><attrdef>Y coordinate of the end of the mapped line segment</attrdef><attrdefs>Producer defined</attrdefs><attrdomv><rdom><rdommin>2800962.0958</rdommin><rdommax>2873495.68186</rdommax><attrunit>meters</attrunit></rdom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>EndX</attrlabl><attrdef>X coordinate of the end of the mapped line segment</attrdef><attrdefs>Producer defined</attrdefs><attrdomv><rdom><rdommin>547316.532283</rdommin><rdommax>583434.982509</rdommax><attrunit>meters</attrunit></rdom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>StartY</attrlabl><attrdef>Y coordinate of the start of the mapped line segment</attrdef><attrdefs>Producer defined</attrdefs><attrdomv><rdom><rdommin>2806283.91817</rdommin><rdommax>2855038.18467</rdommax><attrunit>meters</attrunit></rdom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>StartX</attrlabl><attrdef>X coordinate of the start of the mapped line segment</attrdef><attrdefs>Producer defined</attrdefs><attrdomv><rdom><rdommin>553802.925698</rdommin><rdommax>576983.390591</rdommax><attrunit>meters</attrunit></rdom></attrdomv></attr></detailed><overview><eaover>This table provides information about the mapped line which indicated the approximate inland extent of saltwater intrusion in the Biscayne Aquifer of Miami-Dade County Florida, in 2018.</eaover><eadetcit>Prinos, S.T., 2019, Map of the Approximate Inland Extent of Saltwater at the Base of the Biscayne Aquifer in Miami-Dade County, Florida, 2018: U.S. Geological Survey Scientific Investigations Map 2019–xxxx, xx p. https://doi.org/10.3133/XXXXX.</eadetcit></overview></eainfo><distinfo><distrib><cntinfo><cntorgp><cntorg>U.S. Geological Survey</cntorg><cntper>U.S. Geological Survey - ScienceBase Catalogue</cntper></cntorgp><cntaddr><addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype><address>Denver Federal Center, Building 810,</address><address>Mail Stop 302</address><city>Denver</city><state>CO</state><postal>80225</postal><country>USA</country></cntaddr><cntvoice>1-888-275-8747</cntvoice><cntemail>sciencebase@usgs.gov</cntemail></cntinfo></distrib><resdesc>Downloadable Data</resdesc><distliab>Any use of trade, firm, or product names is for descriptive purposes only and does not imply endorsement by the U.S. Government. Although this information product, for the most part, is in the public domain, it also contains copyrighted materials as noted in the text. Permission to reproduce copyrighted items must be secured from the copyright owner whenever applicable. The data have been approved for release and publication by the U.S. Geological Survey (USGS). Although the data have been subjected to rigorous review and are substantially complete, the USGS reserves the right to revise the data pursuant to further analysis and review. Furthermore, the data are released on the condition that neither the USGS nor the U.S. Government may be held liable for any damages resulting from authorized or unauthorized use. Although the data have been processed successfully on a computer system at the U.S. Geological Survey, no warranty expressed or implied is made regarding the display or utility of the data on any other system, or for general or scientific purposes, nor shall the act of distribution constitute any such warranty. Users of the data are advised to read all metadata and associated documentation thoroughly to understand appropriate use and data limitations</distliab><stdorder><digform><digtinfo><formname>Vector Digital Data Set (Polyline)</formname><formvern>1</formvern><transize>0.006</transize></digtinfo><digtopt><onlinopt><computer><networka><networkr>https://doi.org/10.5066/xxxxxxxxx</networkr></networka></computer></onlinopt></digtopt></digform><fees>none</fees></stdorder></distinfo><metainfo><metd>20190304</metd><metc><cntinfo><cntorgp><cntorg>U.S. Geological Survey, Southeast Region</cntorg><cntper>Scott T Prinos</cntper></cntorgp><cntpos>Hydrologist</cntpos><cntaddr><addrtype>mailing address</addrtype><address>3321 College Avenue</address><city>Davie</city><state>FL</state><postal>33314</postal><country>United States</country></cntaddr><cntvoice>954-377-5944</cntvoice><cntfax>954-377-5901</cntfax><cntemail>stprinos@usgs.gov</cntemail></cntinfo></metc><metstdn>FGDC Content Standard for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn><metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv><mettc>local time</mettc><metextns><onlink>http://www.esri.com/metadata/esriprof80.html</onlink><metprof>ESRI Metadata Profile</metprof></metextns></metainfo><Esri><CreaDate>20190507</CreaDate><CreaTime>12301200</CreaTime><ArcGISFormat>1.0</ArcGISFormat><ArcGISstyle>FGDC CSDGM Metadata</ArcGISstyle><SyncOnce>TRUE</SyncOnce></Esri></metadata>
